(ナルト)多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ハッ！
《クソッ！》
Damn it!
(カカシ)ま… そう焦るなって。
Hey, don't be so impatient.
(カカシ)修業は順調だよ。
あとは 時間の問題だ。
Your training is going well.
Now it's only a matter of time.
時間の問題なら もっともっと➡
If it's just a matter of time,
then you should let me
train nonstop.
修業を続けさせてくれたって
いいじゃねえか！
(カカシ)ん～ お前がタフなのは
わかってんだけどさ…。
I know you're tough, but...
(ヤマト)ボク… ボクなら
いつだって… 大丈夫。
I-I'm ready to go...anytime.
I'm okay!
C-Captain Yamato...
You're scaring me.
ヤマト隊長… 怖いってばよ。
Under the Starry Sky
(角都)次は お前が持て。
You carry him for a while.
(飛段)おいおいおい
金 金言ってんのは テメエだろ！
Hey, hey, hey.
You're the one always
talking about money.
最後まで テメエが運べ！
大事な賞金首だろ。
You carry him all the way.
He's your precious bounty, right?
なんだよ！
その めんどくせえ目はよぉ！
What's with that look?
(角都)お前は いつか必ず
オレが殺してやる。
I'm definitely going to kill you someday.
(飛段)だから
それをオレに言うかよ… 角都！
I told you, don't give me that...Kakuzu.
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
(サクラ)なんだ…
元気にやってるじゃない。
Oh, he's doing fine.
I guess he didn't need my food pills.
兵糧丸なんて いらなかったかな？
I think he does.
(サイ)そうでもないと 思いますよ。
うわ… やだ～ ちょっと
いつから そこにいんのよ!?
Hey!
How long have you been there?
Quite a while before you came.
サクラが来る ずっと前から…。
ウソ！ 全然 気づかなかった…
アンタ 存在感なさすぎ！
No way!
I had no idea...
I didn't even sense your presence.
アハ… すみません…。
I'm sorry.
それより あの修業
見た目 以上に ハードですよ。
More importantly, that training
is a lot tougher than it looks.
Naruto isn't all that skillful
from my viewpoint.
ボクの目から見ても
ナルトは 器用なほうじゃない。
He must sustain complete focus
その彼が
限界に近い影分身を使いながら➡
while using Shadow Clones
nearly to his limit.
集中力を 維持しなければ
ならないんだから…。
疲労の度合いは 通常の修業とは
桁外れでしょうね。
The degree of fatigue
must be extraordinary
compared to that of normal training.
Yes... That's right...
ええ… そうよね…。
That's...
(サイ)…と。
ん？
…この本に書いてありました。
BASICS OF
CHANGE IN CHAKRA NATURE
what it said in this book...
隠すことないのに。
You didn't have to hide anything.
I thought you'd be appalled
to learn...
(サイ)また 本の知識に頼ってと
あきれられるかと…。
I'm still relying on
the knowledge of books.
やっぱり…。
I knew it...
フフフ… ごめん そうじゃないの
そういうのは いいのよ。
I'm sorry.
That's not what I meant.
It's perfectly fine.
だって 仲間のことが
心配だから調べたんでしょう。
After all, you read up on it
because you're worried
about your friends, right?
Books come in handy at times like that.
本はね そういうときにこそ
役に立つのよ。
You actually do  have
a nice side to you.
アンタ 優しいとこ あるんじゃない。
えっ！ ボクが優しい…。
What? I'm nice...?
Okay, let's go
so we won't interfere with his training.
さぁ 修業の邪魔にならないように
私たちは行きましょう。
I guess they shaped up into
a good team while I was away.
《オレのいない間に いいチームに
まとまってたのかな？》
Well, that's good.
《ま いいことだよね》
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
はっ！
ナルト～！
Naruto!
いったん 影分身を解くんだ。
Break the Shadow Clone Jutsu for a bit
これまでの修業の成果を
反芻しながらな。
and mull over the results
of your current training.
Accumulate your experience.
(カカシ)経験値の蓄積だ！
オッス！
Right!
どうだ？ 実感あるか？
So? Can you feel it?
この程度じゃ まだだ…。
I've still got a ways to go.
修業を続けるってばよ…。
I'm going to continue the training...
だから ムリしすぎなんだって。
You're overdoing it, I tell you.
それは？
サクラからの差し入れだ。
What's that?
Sakura brought it for you.
These are food pills...
and there's a note inside.
兵糧丸と メモが入ってる。
Eat one of my special food pills
and keep up the training. - Sakura
サクラちゃん…。
Sakura...
ハハハ！ サクラちゃんの手作り兵糧丸
いただくってばよ！
Sakura's home-made food pills.
Let's eat!
まずっ!! って サクラちゃん！
Sakura, these are totally inedible.
とてもじゃねえが
食えねえってばよ。
おし！ 修業再開だ！
Okay, time to continue training!
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
はっ！
はっ！ はっ！
《フフッ あのナルトが 修業を
こんなに続けられるのも➡
I bet Naruto has been able to
continue training
きっと 私の兵糧丸のおかげね》
because of my food pills.
す すごい…。
W-Wow!
(カカシ)ナルト！
少しは休憩したらどうだ？
Naruto! Why don't you take
a little break?
I can't catch up to Sasuke
if I throw in the towel now!
こんなんで 音を上げてたんじゃ➡
いつまでたっても
サスケにゃ追いつけねえってばよ！
MEDICINAL HERBS
Well, if it isn't Sakura.
(イルカ)サクラじゃないか！
(サクラ)あぁ！ イルカ先生！
Oh, Iruka Sensei.
(イルカ)いや～ ナルトも
たいしたもんだよな。
Wow, Naruto sure is something else.
里のピンチに大活躍だもんな。
He did a great job during
the village's dilemma.
私だって活躍しました。
なんちゃって。
I did, too!
Just kidding.
ハハハ すまん すまん。
Sorry, sorry.
You've become
Lady Tsunade's apprentice, after all.
サクラも 綱手様の弟子になったし➡
優秀な生徒を持ったオレは
鼻が高いよ。
I'm so proud to have had
such excellent students.
特に おちこぼれの生徒は
かわいいもんさ。
My drop-out students are
particularly lovable.
Even now, Naruto's continuing with
training that only he can do, right?
今だって ナルトにしかできない
すごい修業を続けてるんだろ？
たいしたもんだ。
That's really something.
私は 最初から優秀でしたからね。
I was excellent right from the start.
かわいい生徒じゃなくて
すみませんでした。
Sorry I wasn't a lovable student.
Oh, come on.
You sure are giving me grief today.
おいおい 今日は やけに絡むなぁ。
エヘヘッ。 でも ホント アイツは強くなった。
But he sure got stronger.
Yeah. He's changed.
Everyone's changing.
あぁ 変わった。
みんな変わっていく。
My students are growing up
strong and steadfast.
(イルカ)強く たくましく
オレの生徒は成長していくんだ。
(イズモ)ん？ あれは…。
What's that?
(綱手)そうか…。
あの地陸までも…。
I see...
They even got Chiriku, huh...?
自分は ちょうど巡警に出ていて➡
I was out on patrol...
帰ってきたときには もう…。
and by the time I returned,
it was too late.
(シズネ)おそらく 暁の連中➡
It was most likely the guys
from the Akatsuki.
火ノ国で
人柱力のいそうな場所を➡
They're probably going one by one
to locations in the Land of Fire
しらみつぶしに
してるのでしょう。
where there might be a Jinchuriki.
ついに… 来ましたね。
Finally they've come.
火ノ国から逃がすな。
We won't let them out
of the Land of Fire.
新編成した 二十小隊に
ただちに連絡しろ！
Contact the twenty newly formed
platoons immediately!
話は ここまでだ。
That's all I have to say.
何か質問がある者は いるか？
Does anyone have any questions?
何だ？
What is it?
(アスマ)あそこには
元 守護忍十二士の➡
Chiriku, a former member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
地陸がいるはずです。
彼は どうなったんです？
should be there.
What happened to him?
地陸様は ソヤツらの手にかかり…➡
Lord Chiriku died by their hands.
亡くなりました。
《あの地陸が… バカな！》
Chiriku was killed?
It can't be...
(綱手)木ノ葉の威信にかけても➡
For the pride of the Hidden Leaf,
and most of all,
何より 火ノ国の安全のためにも➡
for the safety of the Land of Fire,
ヤツらを これ以上 野放しに
しておくわけにはいかない！
we must not let them rampage
any further.
(綱手)ヤツらの目的も知りたいが
かなりの手練だ。
I want to know what they're after,
but they're very dangerous.
火ノ国から 絶対に逃がすな！
Don't let them out of the Land of Fire,
no matter what.
必ず見つけ出し
身柄の拘束が不可能な場合➡
Find them without fail and
if you're unable to restrain them,
抹殺しろ！ 行け！ 散！
kill them!
Go!
Dismissed!
《いの : 元 アスマ班の名を
汚さないよう…》
I will do my best, and I won't bring
shame to the former Team Asuma.
《チョウジ : がんばるからね
シカマル アスマ先生！》
We'll do our best,
Shikamaru, Asuma Sensei!
(シカマル)さて…。
Now then...
Okay, we'll start with
the Temple of Fire.
じゃあ オレたちは
火ノ寺からあたるぞ。
誰かが やらなきゃな…。
Someone has to do it.
(アスマ)行くぞ！
Let's go.
アスマ先生。
なんだ？
Asuma Sensei...
What is it?
アンタ 火ノ寺の地陸って人と
知り合いっぽかったが。
It seems you were acquainted
with Chiriku from the Temple of Fire.
あぁ 言ってなかったか？
Yeah... Didn't I tell you?
昔の戦友だ。
We used to be brothers-in-arms.
オレが 木ノ葉を離れ➡
It was around the time
when I left the Hidden Leaf
守護忍十二士なんて
呼ばれてた頃のな。
and was known as one of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
火ノ寺は近い！ 急ぐぞ！
The Temple of Fire is close.
Let's hurry!
(サクラ)月が きれい。
The moon sure is beautiful.
((ヘヘヘ！
はぁ～ サクラちゃんってば
すっげえ！
You're awesome, Sakura!
Just what I'd expect from
the girl I knew you'd be!
(さすが オレの見込んだ女！))
((みんな 変わっていく))
Everyone's changing.
《そう 変わってしまった…》
That's right. Everyone's changed.
《サクラ : ナルトは サスケ君を追いかけて➡
Naruto is continuing with
his training that nobody else can do...
誰にも できないような修業を
続けている》
all to pursue Sasuke.
((イテテテ…。
(サスケ)フン！
アハハ！ ナルトったら))
Oh, Naruto...
《私ができるのは
ほんの小さなことだけ》
I can only do little things for him.
((ヤマト : できることの
大きい小さいは 問題じゃないよ。
It's not the size of the things
you can do that matters.
(大切なのは
ナルトを思う気持の大きさでしょ))
What's important is the strength
of your feelings for Naruto.
流れ星か。
A shooting star, huh?
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu.
はっ！ はっ！ はっ！
はっ！ はっ！
クソッ！
Damn it!
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
《でもよ オレが折れなきゃ…➡
As long as I don't give in
and keep going without
stopping to rest...
オレが 休まず歩き続けりゃ…➡
I'll arrive at the point where...
いつか たどり着くよな》
いくぞ～！ はっ！
Here we go!
All right!
よっしゃ！
(ヤマト)この修業は
なかなかのもんですね。
This training is something else, isn't it?
あのナルトが こんなに早く…。
Naruto is progressing
so quickly.
(カカシ)いや この修業方法の
おかげばかりじゃないよ。
No... It's not just because
of this training approach.
(カカシ)サスケが そうさせるんだ。
Sasuke has something
to do with it, too.
- We cut the waterfall!
- We really cut it!
滝 切れたってばよ！ マジ 切れた!!
フゥ…。
(カカシ)よくやった。
Well done.
Now we can start development
of your new original Jutsu.
これで 次からは
オリジナルの新術開発に入る。
ハァ ハァ… わかったってば。
Right... I got it...
You okay, Naruto?!
大丈夫か ナルト？
《少し やりすぎたか》
I guess he overdid it a little.
Wh-What is it?
な… なんだ？
は… 腹… 減った…。
I'm...hungry...
《本当に
たいしたヤツだよ お前は》
You really are...something else.
ダ～ッ！ カカシ先生 今日も遅刻かよ。
まぁ いつものことだけど。
おっ そうだ！
え!?
グフフフ…。
何よ？
(カカシ)いや～ 遅刻 遅刻。
ふぇ～ もう１歩たりとも動けん。
いや～ すまないねぇ。
いえ いえ いえ。
Shizune, have we figured out
what they're up to?
ところで
おばあさんの家は まだですか？
Using the twenty platoons,
へい。
ん？ なに～!?
we are currently laying out
a search net
with a radius of 150 kilometers around
the border and the Temple of Fire.
あぁ えらい目にあった。
じっとしてて！
今 助けてあげるよ！
And...it seems they have not yet
encountered the Akatsuki.
(カカシ)どうしたの キミたち？
Why not?
We laid down a search net
(カカシ)ネコ？
(２人)ありがとう おじちゃん。
(カカシ)お おじちゃん!?
(２人)じゃあね！
(カカシ)アハハハ…。
あぁ… 今日は なんて日なんだ…。
たまには いい薬よね。
いい気味じゃ。 ニヒヒ！